Finding Aid for Andrew W. Tanner Photographs 1894-1909
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Andrew W. Tanner Photographs
1894-1909
Tanner, Andrew W.
Andrew Tanner was photographer, born in Missouri, who traveled about the United States. He lived for a time in Ann Arbor, Michigan and on Coryell Island (part of the Les Cheneaux Islands) in Michigan's Upper Peninsula. The collection consists of glass plate negatives of images taken while in different parts of the United States and Mexico.
0386 Aa 2
15 linear feet including 280 glass plate negatives and 2 videotapes
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection was received from Betsy Kausch (donor no. 9198 ) in July and November 2002, February 2005, and May 2013.
The collection is open for research.
Little is known about Andrew Wineland Tanner, the photographer who created the images in this collection. He was born ca. 1856 in Missouri, according to the 1930 Federal Census. Tanner married Ria Waite at some point in the 1870s, and the couple had at least one child, Volney, who was born ca. 1882. Tanner married Ella Wagner in 1925 (according to a memoir in Ripples from the Breezes, edited by Philip Pittman, p. 97), and the couple lived in Ann Arbor, Michigan at the time of the 1930 census.
It is unknown what allowed Tanner to travel around the country taking these photographs, although it appears likely that he and his brothers -- Charles and James -- were co-owners of a merchandising chain called Tanner Bros. General Stores. (See The National Cyclopaedia of American Biography entry for Allen Barnett Tanner, pictured in this collection, vol. 44, 1961-1964, pp. 415-416.)
Andrew's brother Charles purchased land on Coryell Island (part of Les Cheneaux) in 1897 (the sale was finalized in September 1897, according to the Mackinac Co. Letter Book, 1895-1910 held at this library), and the two built homes there at some point thereafter. Ripples from the Breezes notes that Andrew and Charles Tanner by 1905 "had completed one of the most individualistic, complete, and systematic cottage settlements in Les Cheneaux" (p. 28) with a "little Dutch wind-mill at the shore line, which housed their water system" (p. 28), and these cottages are well-documented in the images in the collection.
Tanner's land on Les Cheneaux was purchased by S.P. Upham sometime in the late 1930s or early 1940s (Ripples from the Breezes, p. 374), and later by Jack Kausch, who came into possession of the photograph collection.
The Andrew Tanner Photograph Collection includes glass plate negatives from his travels across the United State and in Mexico in the late 19th and early 20th centuries. Images in the collection demonstrate in a vivid way life in the United States, the natural environment, and the photographic processes of the time. The plates are in excellent condition and images are of very good quality. Tanner's original plate numbers are indicated on the slides, and where known, are indicated on the sleeves containing the plates; some plates were also assigned numbers by their intermediate owner, Jack Kausch, and, where known, these are also indicated on the envelopes. The images in the collection (14 boxes) date from 1894 to 1909, and are organized into three series: 5x7 Plates, 1894-1909 (13 boxes), 8x10 Plates, ca. 1900 (1 linear foot), and Miscellaneous (1 linear foot).
Subjects - Visual Material:
Tanner, Andrew W.; Colorado Springs (Colo.); Emporia (Kan.); Hot Springs (Ark.); Juarez (Mexico); Les Cheneaux Islands (Mich.); Mackinac Island (Mich.); Mexico.; Resorts--Michigan.; Saint Louis (Mo.); Tanner family.; Topeka (Kan.)
Contributors:
Kausch, Jack.
Genre/Form:
Glass negatives.; Videotapes.; Photographs.
- 5 x 7" Glass Plates
  The 5x7 Plates, 1894-1909 Series includes approximately 230 plates. Of particular interest and depth are the plates relating to the Garden of the Gods (Colorado), St. Louis, Mackinac Island and Les Cheneaux, as well as Tanner family portraits.
  - Localities
    - Arkansas
      - Hot Springs
        - Bonanza Springs
          - Brook, April 15, 1898 (Box 1)
          - Brook, April 15, 1898 (Box 1)
          - Brook, April 15, 1898 (Box 1)
          - Brook, April 16, 1898 (Box 1)
          - Roaring Brook (some color added), April 15, 1898 (Box 1)
          - Roaring Brook, April 16, 1898 (Box 1)
          - Roaring Brook, April 16, 1898 (Box 1)
          - Roaring Brook, April 16, 1898 (Box 1)
          - Roaring Brook, April 16, 1898 (Box 1)
        - Brook and Wooded Area, April 13, 1898 (Box 1)
        - Brook in Woods, April 13, 1898 (Box 1)
        - Brook in Woods, April 30, 1898 (Box 1)
        - Burro and Make-shift Tent, "Home Sweet Home,", April 30, 1898 (Box 1)
        - Entrance to Hot Springs Mountain Baths, Historic Buildings, April 30, 1898 (Box 1)
        - Government Hospital, April 1898 (Box 1)
        - Group of Men and Women with Burros, "Burro Party,", undated (Box 1)
        - Hale Springs, May 30, 1898 (Box 1)
        - View of Hills, Water Works, and Lakes, April 12, 1898 (Box 1)
      - Unidentified location
        - Road with Split-Rail Fence alongside and Trees all around, undated (Box 1)
    - California
      - San Gabriel Mission, 1909 (Box 2)
    - Colorado
      - Cascade
        - Ria, Mrs. Hazelton & Harry on Burros, Gazebo in Background, September 1900 (Box 2)
      - Colorado Springs
        - Garden of the Gods
          - Balance Rock, September 1900 (Box 2)
          - Blacksmith Anvil, September 1900 (Box 2)
          - Cathedral Spires, September 1900 (Box 2)
          - Gateway, September 1900 (Box 2)
          - Gateway, September 1900 (Box 2)
          - Gateway, September 1900 (Box 2)
          - Pulpit Rock, September 1900 (Box 2)
          - Spires, September 1900 (Box 2)
          - Toad and Two Stools, September 1900 (Box 2)
          - View, Garden of the Gods, September 1900 (Box 2)
          - View, Garden of the Gods, September 1900 (Box 2)
          - View, Garden of the Gods (like above), September 1900 (Box 2)
    - Kansas
      - Emporia
        - 709 Exchange Street, Workshop, May 1901 (Box 2)
        - 1128 Market Street
          - Dining Room, April 1906 (Box 2)
          - Interior Hall, April 1906 (Box 2)
          - Parlor, April 1906 (Box 2)
          - Parlor, April 1906 (Box 2)
          - View of House (North Side), April 1906 (Box 2)
          - Workshop, 1904 (Box 2)
        - Cottonwood River, May 1899 (Box 2)
        - Dam and Waterworks, Boy in Foreground and Men in Background Fishing, May 1899 (Box 3)
        - Normal School, May 1899 (Box 3)
        - Patty's Mill (Ruins), May 1899 (Box 3)
        - Patty's Mill, at a Distance (Ruins), May 1899 (Box 3)
        - Mill Dam at Thompson Mill (Close-Up), May 1899 (Box 3)
        - Mill Dam at Thompson Mill (From a Distance), May 1899 (Box 3)
        - Neosho River
          - Neosho River and Trees Along Bank, May 1899 (Box 3)
          - Neosho River, View from Bank to Bank, May 1899 (Box 3)
          - Neosho River, View from Bank to Bank, May 1899 (Box 3)
          - Timber Road and Neosho River, May 1899 (Box 3)
          - Trees and Banks of Neosho River, May 1899 (Box 3)
          - Trees and Timber Road along Neosho River, May 1899 (Box 3)
          - Woods along Neosho River, undated (Box 3)
        - Soden Grove Trees, May 1899 (Box 3)
        - Soden Grove View (Tall Trees, Picnic Benches, Two Women amongst Trees), May 1899 (Box 3)
        - Soden Mill and Dam on Cottonwood River, May 1899 (Box 3)
        - Tanner Residence, Exterior, May 1899 (Box 3)
        - Two Men Leaning Against Tree on Bank of Cottonwood River, Fishing, May 1899 (Box 3)
        - Unidentified Waterway with Trees along Banks (Priddle?), May 1899 (Box 3)
        - Water with Fence Running Through it, Trees in Background (Priddle?), May 1899 (Box 3)
      - Topeka
        - Dining Room, Unidentified Taylor Street Home, circa 1900 (Box 4)
        - Parlor, Unidentified Taylor Street Home, circa 1900 (Box 4)
        - Parlor, Unidentified Taylor Street Home, circa 1900 (Box 4)
        - Parlor, Unidentified Taylor Street Home, circa 1900 (Box 4)
        - Sitting Room, Unidentified Taylor Street Home, circa 1900 (Box 4)
    - Michigan
      - Les Cheneaux
        - Bear Rug (Close-up) (Box 4)
        - Bear Rug (Box 4)
        - Bettie (Boat), 1907 (Box 4)
        - Birdhouses (four) sitting on table, circa 1900 (Box 4)
        - Birdhouses (?) (Box 4)
          (close-up)
        - Boathouse with Boat Eleanor Entering, 1907 (Box 4)
        - Boathouse from Williams' Dock, 1907 (Box 4)
        - Boathouse from Tanner Dock, 1907 (Box 4)
        - Boats in Bushes Bay, 1906 (Box 4)
        - Charles and Volney Tanner in Rowboat Helen T, 1906 (Box 4)
        - Cottages
          - Kilkare (Charles J. Tanner Cottage)
            - Back of Cottage, Snows, 1905 (Box 4)
            - Combination of photographs of Kilkare, 1907 (Box 4)
            - Exterior, including Ornate Sign Hanging in Front, circa 1900 (Box 4)
            - Exterior, 1905 (Box 4)
            - Exterior, 1906 (Box 4)
            - Interior, East Side, 1907 (Box 4)
            - Interior, West Side, 1907 (Box 4)
          - The Tannery (Andrew Tanner's Property)
            - The Ark
              - Building the Chimney, September 1904 (Box 5)
              - Cabin, September 1904 (Box 5)
              - Front View, September 1904 (Box 5)
              - Interior, September 1904 (Box 5)
              - Interior, with Ducks Hanging above Fireplace, September 1904 (Box 5)
              - Side View, September 1904 (Box 5)
              - Sign Post (Box 5)
              - View from Dock, 1907 (Box 5)
            - Sign, The Tannery, and View Over Dock, circa 1900 (Box 5)
            - Windmill
              - Windmill and View Along Beach, circa 1900 (Box 5)
              - Windmill and View of Tannery from Water, circa 1900 (Box 5)
              - Windmill, Tannery, and Dock, from Water, circa 1900 (Box 5)
          - Unidentified Cottages
            - Cottage in Woods, circa 1900 (Box 5)
            - Interior of Cottage, West Side at the Snows, 1905 (Box 5)
            - Oilhouse at the Snows, 1905 (Box 5)
            - Side View Cottage, Snows, 1905 (Box 5)
            - View Looking out Dining Room Windows at the Snows, 1905 (Box 5)
        - Ducks hanging on line, boy standing behind, holding a gun, circa 1900 (Box 5)
        - Boy standing with gun in front of dead birds on dock (Box 5)
        - Eleanor (Boat), Tied to Dock, September 1904 (Box 5)
        - Eleanor (Boat), September 1904 (Box 5)
        - Fishing Boat (Box 5)
        - Group Events
          - Andrew Tanner's Family in Sailboat Helen T, 1897 (Box 5)
          - Andrew Tanner Family Group, on Rock at Elliott House (Box 6)
          - Fish Fry, Men and Women at "The Snows", August 1899 (Box 6)
          - Fish Fry, August 1903 (Box 6)
          - Fish Fry at Bushes Bay, 1906 (Box 6)
          - Fish Fry at McGulpin Channel, Men and Women Eating, 1906 (Box 6)
          - Fish Fry on Government Dock, August 11, 1896 (Box 6)
          - Group (Men, Women, Children) Gathered by Lake, August 1902 (Box 6)
          - Group Picnicking in Woods, along Lake, August 1902 (Box 6)
          - Picnic Group at Government Is, circa 1900 (Box 6)
          - Picnic Party at Bosley Channel, August 1, 1898 (Box 6)
          - "Sunday Dinner" Series (Picnic Setting)
            - Four Men Standing Against A Tree, July 1903 (Box 6)
            - Men and Women in Picnic Setting, July 1903 (Box 6)
            - Men and Women in Picnic Setting, July 1903 (Box 6)
            - Women Seated, Picnicking, July 1903 (Box 6)
            - Women Standing Around Tree, Hands Reaching out from Behind Tree, July 1903 (Box 6)
        - Individuals
          - Juliet (?) Holding Oar, on Rock Near Water, 1895 (Box 6)
          - Child (Juliet?) with Toy Sailing Boat, 1895 (Box 6)
          - McSemmons (?) Bathing off Tanner Dock, boat Helen T in Foreground, 1906 (Box 6)
          - McSemmons (?) Bathing off Tanner Dock, 1906 (Box 6)
          - Miss Horner and Miss Winans, in Dresses, Posing in Yard, 1894 (Box 6)
          - Miss Sams, with Hat On Head, Standing on Rock in Water, 1895 (Box 6)
          - Miss Sams, Standing on Rock in Water, 1895 (Box 7)
        - Leopard Skin Rug (Box 7)
        - Man Smoking a Pipe, Standing in Woods, circa 1900 (Box 7)
        - Man Walking Down Dock with Dead Ducks in Both Hands, circa 1900 (Box 7)
        - Palmer Brothers (George and Lon), Guides at Lakeside Hotel, Making Ice Fishing Lures, circa 1900 (Box 7)
        - Photo Cabinet, Showing Materials and Supplies for Developing Photos, 1905 (Box 7)
        - Turnstile and Fence in Woods, circa 1900 (Box 7)
      - Mackinac Island
        - Arch Rock Road, 1897 (Box 7)
        - Birch Trees, September 1901 (Box 7)
        - Birch Trees at Look Out, September 1901 (Box 7)
        - Cows on the Island, Woods in Background, 1897 (Box 7)
        - Crib Road, With Fence Alongside, September 1901 (Box 7)
        - Crooked Trees, September 1901 (Box 7)
        - Crooked Trees, September 1901 (Box 7)
        - Forked Birch, Path, and Woods, September 1901 (Box 7)
        - Huron Street View, Including St. Anne's Church, September 1899 (Box 7)
        - Lake Drive Road, 1897 (Box 7)
        - Lake Shore Drive, September 1901 (Box 7)
        - Lake Shore Drive, West, Tree Stumps, October 1, 1898 (Box 7)
        - Lake Shore Road, Bridge and Brook, October 1, 1898 (Box 7)
        - Leslie Arc Road, 1897 (Box 7)
        - Leslie Arc Road, Large Birch Tree, September 1901 (Box 8)
        - Leslie Avenue, Six Birch Trees alongside, September 28, 1898 (Box 8)
        - Mrs. A. E. Davis Cottage, circa 1900 (Box 8)
        - Path through Woods, undated (Box 8)
        - Path through Woods, 1897 (Box 8)
        - Path through Woods, 1897 (Box 8)
        - Path through Woods, Fence in Background (Box 8)
        - Robinson's Folly, undated (Box 8)
        - Robinson's Folly, Road Underneath, August 1902 (Box 8)
        - Shore Drive by Rock, September 1901 (Box 8)
        - Storm with Waves Rolling in, September 1907 (Box 8)
    - Mexico
      - Guadalupe
        - Church Exterior and Bell Tower, 1894 (Box 8)
        - Church Exterior and Bell Tower, Men Posed at Side, 1894 (Box 8)
        - Church Interior, 1894 (Box 8)
      - Juarez
        - Booths in Street, Men Gathered Talking and Buying, circa 1895 (Box 8)
        - Gonzalez Liquor & Cigar Store, circa 1895 (Box 8)
        - Post Office Building (Administracion de Correos), 1894 (Box 8)
        - View of City, Mountain in Background, 1894 (Box 8)
      - Unidentified Location
        - Country Road, Trees Along Fence, Building along Roadside, circa 1894 (Box 8)
        - Patio of Unidentified Building (Some color added), circa 1895 (Box 8)
        - View of Streets, with Booths and People, circa 1894 (Box 8)
    - Missouri
      - St. Louis
        - Potted Palms in Shaw's Garden, July 1, 1896 (Box 9)
        - Tower Grove Park, King's Highway, West Gate Entrance, July 1, 1896 (Box 9)
        - Waterslide and Rafts into River, "Shooting the Shoots", July 5, 1896 (Box 9)
      - Unidentified Location
        - Grey Eagle Steamer at Landing on Mississippi River, July 10, 1896 (Box 9)
        - Landing on Mississippi River, Ships Grey Eagle and Park Bluff at Dock, People In Line, July 10, 1896 (Box 9)
        - Loading Hogs onto the Grey Eagle (St. Louis -- Memphis) along the Mississippi River, July 10, 1896 (Box 9)
        - Locks on Mississippi River, July 10, 1896 (Box 9)
        - Locks on Mississippi River, Paddlewheel Ruth in lock, July 10, 1896 (Box 9)
        - Locks on Mississippi River, Paddlewheel Vixen upstream, July 10, 1896 (Box 9)
        - Men Playing Craps on Mississippi River, July 10, 1896 (Box 9)
        - View of the Mississippi River, July 10, 1896 (Box 9)
    - Texas
      - El Paso
        - Two Boys Sitting on Crate, Eating, 1894 (Box 9)
        - Two Boys Sitting on Crate, Playing, 1894 (Box 9)
        - Volney Tanner and Mildred, Standing Outside with Dogs (Scratched Plate), 1895 (Box 9)
        - Volney Tanner and Mildred, Standing Outside with Dogs (Copy Plate), 1895 (Box 9)
        - Volney Tanner on Burro, in Front of Jerowland Shoes Store, 1895 (Box 9)
    - Unidentified Location
      - Buchanan Street (Tanner's Brother Jim's home)
        - Dining Room, December 30, 1895 (Box 9)
        - Parlor, Decorated for Christmas, December 30, 1895 (Box 9)
      - Davenport House
        - Dining Room, undated (Box 9)
          (print in Box 13)
        - Dining Room, undated (Box 9)
          print in Box 13
        - Exterior View, undated (Box 9)
        - Exterior View, Children Sitting on Porch, undated (Box 10)
        - Exterior View, People Sitting on Porch, undated (Box 10)
        - Reception Hall, undated (Box 10)
      - "Hot House" (Greenhouse)
        - Exterior, North End, January 10, 1907 (Box 10)
        - Exterior, South End, January 10, 1907 (Box 10)
        - Interior, Plants Growing in Buckets, January 1907 (Box 10)
      - Industry along the Chicago River, undated (Box 10)
      - Man with Three Loaded Mules, undated (Box 10)
      - Steamship Northwest, undated (Box 10)
      - View from Center of Railroad Track Looking over Ratune Range, 1894 (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Flower Study
      - Dahlias, September 25, 1898 (Box 10)
      - Dahlias, September 25, 1898 (Box 10)
      - Peonies in Vase, May 1899 (Box 10)
  - Portraits
    - Allen Barnett Tanner
      - In Dress in Chair, St. Louis, Missouri, April 1899 (Box 10)
      - In Dress (Baptism?), St. Louis, Missouri, 1900 (Box 10)
      - In Padded Knickers, St. Louis, Missouri, 1907 (Box 10)
      - In Sailor Outfit, St. Louis Missouri, circa 1900 (Box 10)
        Split Plate
      - In Scottish Outfit, St. Louis, Missouri, circa 1900 (Box 10)
      - In Scottish Outfit, St. Louis, Missouri, circa 1900 (Box 10)
      - In Scottish Outfit, St. Louis, Missouri, circa 1900 (Box 10)
      - In Dress, St. Louis, Missouri, circa 1900 (Box 10)
    - Andrew W. Tanner
      - (By S.H. Waite), 1898 (Box 11)
      - (By S.H. Waite), 1898 (Box 11)
      - 1900 (Box 11)
      - 1901 (Box 11)
      - Undated (Box 11)
      - Undated (Box 11)
        (odd camera angle)
      - On a front porch (Box 11)
    - Charles J. Tanner, St. Louis, Missouri, April 1899 (Box 11)
      (see also 6.5x8.5 in box 14)
    - Harriet Tanner
      - Close-up in Wicker Chair, December 27, 1896 (Box 11)
      - Close-up In Wicker Chair, December 27, 1896; Retouched (Box 11)
      - Seated, in Sitting Room, December 27, 1896 (Box 11)
      - Seated, in Sitting Room, December 27, 1896; Like previous, but better quality (Box 11)
      - Outdoors, in Yard, circa 1896 (Box 11)
    - H. M. Tanner
      - St. Louis, Missouri, April 1899 (Box 11)
      - St. Louis, Missouri, April 1899 (Box 11)
      - St. Louis, Missouri, April 1899 (Box 11)
    - Helen Tanner
      - Looking over porch railing, May 21, 1896 (Box 11)
      - With Doll Carriage, May 21, 1896 (Box 11)
      - Playing with Tea Set, October 1897 (Box 11)
      - Seated at Child's Table, October 1897 (Box 11)
      - In Sailor Dress, April 1899 (Box 11)
      - With Nurse, circa 1895 (Box 11)
      - With Mar/Mae on Steps in Hall, circa 1895 (Box 12)
      - With Mar/Mae on Steps in Hall, circa 1895 (Box 12)
      - In Chair, circa 1896; Split Plate (Box 12)
    - James M. Tanner Sr. (from painting) (Box 12)
    - James M. Tanner Jr.
      - February 25, 1899, Retouched (Box 12)
      - February 25, 1899, Retouched (Box 12)
      - February 25, 1899 (Box 12)
      - circa 1899 (Box 12)
      - As child (From painting) (Box 12)
      - With Allen Tanner on Swing, circa 1905 (Box 12)
    - Mar/Mae Tanner
      - With Two Children, St. Louis, Missouri, April 1, 1899 (Box 12)
      - With Two Children, St. Louis, Missouri, April 1899 (Box 12)
      - With Helen, circa 1896; Retouched (Box 12)
      - circa 1895 (Box 12)
      - circa 1895 (Box 12)
    - Ria Tanner
      - Wearing Extravagant Hat, November 1898 (Box 12)
      - Wearing Extravagant Hat, November 1898 (Box 12)
      - Seated in Chair, November 1898 (Box 12)
      - November 1898, Plate is painted (Box 12)
      - November 1898, Some color added (Box 12)
    - Volney M. Tanner
      - Reading a Book in Chair, December 20, 1896 (Box 13)
      - Seated, 1898 (Box 13)
      - Seated in Chair, 1898 (Box 13)
      - Full-length, Standing, 1898 (Box 13)
      - February 1, 1899, Retouched (Box 13)
      - February 1, 1899, Retouched (Box 13)
      - February 1, 1899, Retouched (Box 13)
      - 1900 (Box 13)
      - 1900 (Box 13)
      - Copy of portrait done as Child, circa 1887 (Box 13)
      - With Burro's Head Looking over his Shoulder (S.H. Waite Plate), circa 1890 (Box 13)
      - (S.H. Waite Plate), circa 1890 (Box 13)
      - On Bicycle, circa 1893 (Box 13)
      - Standing Beside Chair, circa 1895 (Box 13)
      - With Helen (infant), circa 1895 (Box 13)
      - Standing Beside Tens of Fishes Hanging from Tree, circa 1895 (Box 13)
      - Sitting in Lawn Chair, Les Cheneaux, circa 1900 (Box 13)
    - T.D. Heed
      - Copy of Larger Crayon Portrait (Box 13)
    - Unidentified (Box 13)
      - Group of 5 in woods at opening of fence (Box 13)
      - 2 unidentified men (Box 13)
  - Prints of 5x7 plates (Box 13)
- 6-1/2 x 8-1/2 Plates
  - Unidentified location
    - Portrait of Charles J. Tanner, 1900 (Box 13)
    - Portrait of Ria Waite (Tanner) (Box 13)
- 8 x 10 Glass Plates
  The 8x10 Plates, ca. 1900 Series contains approximately 50 plates, largely documenting life on Mackinac Island and Les Cheneaux. These plates do not duplicate the plates in the 5x7 series.
  - Arkansas
    - Trees on the Hot Spring Mountain, circa 1900 (Box 14)
  - Kansas
    - Cottonwood Trees on Cottonwood River, circa 1900 (Box 14)
  - Michigan
    - Mackinac Island
      - View looking east along Huron Street, circa 1900 (Box 14)
        Shops visible include National Park Indian Bazaar, Bogan's Drug Store, Bailey's Drug Store, and Huyler's Bonbons and Chocolate
      - View of bay, men and women on dock and boardwalk, sailboats and canoes in bay, circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - Cows in Army Pasture, Fort in background, circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - Steamship (Winter or Wintah) in bay, town in background, circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - Sailboats in bay, town in background, circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - View of streets and town in distance, circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - Ships Iron Queen and Iron King at Mackinac dock, circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - Signpost at intersection of roads in woods indicating direction to Annex, Cemetery, and British Landing, circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - Men and women in horse-drawn wagon, Garden and Fort in background, circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - Bennett Hall Hotel, patrons standing on porch, children along fence in foreground, circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - View of street and buildings along harbor, circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - Large Steamship docked at Mackinac Bay, circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - Canton of Detroit sailboat at Mackinac dock, circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - Arch Rock, group standing alongside (Similar to below), circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - Arch Rock, group standing alongside (Similar to above), circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - Arch Rock, group standing alongside, circa 1900 (Box 14)
        (Similar to above)
      - Hoban Cottage(boarding house) and Windsor Hotel, circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - Windsor Hotel, circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - Fort and garden (Similar to below), circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - Fort and garden (Similar to above), circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - Fort and church in foreground, taken from Army Pasture (now Grand Hotel Golf Course ?), circa 1900 (Box 14)
      - Tree Stump in Clearing in Woods, circa 1900 (Box 14)